All right, that was a really challenging coding task.
好了, 那是一個很有挑戰性的編碼任務。
It had many parts to it and it involved a view that you've never used before.
有很多部份而包括了你從未看過的顯示。
Let's walk through the solution together.
讓我們一起走過解決方法。
To start, I asked you to plan out the steps that you need to do.
要開始, 我請你先計劃你要做的步驟。
The first step should be to add this text field so
第一步是要加這文字地方
that the user can enter in their name.
讓用者可以輸入他們的名字。
The second step is that when the order button is clicked,
第二步是當命令按鈕被按，
we want to get the name from the text field and store it in a variable.
我但想於文字地方取得名字之後儲存為一個可變項。
Then the third step is to update the order summary to actually
之後第三步是要更新總結次序去
show that name.
顯示名字。
Let's dive into this first step.
讓我們潛入第一步。
We haven't added a text input field in our app before, so
我們未曾加過文字輸入地方於我們的程式內, 所以
let's Google search for how to do this.
讓我們谷歌搜尋該如何做。
Since we're trying to get input from the user,
由於我們要從用者那裡拿到輸入，
I'm going to search for user input android.
我會搜尋用者輸入機械。
The result is a developer.android.com site, so that looks good.
結果是發展機械工地, 這看來很好。
This page describes best practices for user input.
這頁最好形容用者輸入。
It talks about touch gestures, as well as keyboard input and game controllers.
這說明艱難動作及健盤遊戲控制輸入。
Keyboard input is what we want, so let's click on the first link.
健盤輸入是我們想要的, 我但按下第一連結。
I start by scrolling through the page quickly.
我開始快速滑過頁面。
I see a bunch of XML examples, which will be helpful.
我看到一堆XML例子, 這會很有幫助。
I notice that there is an opening angle bracket and then the view name.
我留意到有開號之後顯示名字。
In this case the view name seems to be EditText.
在這情況顯示名字似乎是改文字。
If I scroll through the other examples, I also see that it's an EditText view.
若我滑過其他例子, 我也可以看到改文字顯示。
So, it seems like this view that takes in keyboard input is called EditText.
所以, 看來這健盤輸入叫作改文字。
Another approach is to use the Common Android Views cheat sheet.
另一個方法是用普通機械顯示片。
The EditText is also in this list of views and
改文字亦於顯示清單內及
this album description example is similar to the name field in our app.
這冊子形容例子與程式內的名字地方相似
Let's copy this XMLand add it into our app.
讓我們複製這XML及加到我們的程式中。
We want the name field at the very top of our order form,
我們想要名字地方於表格的最上方，
above the toppings header, so let's add it here.
於題目方, 讓我們在此加上。
Immediately, there's an error saying that it can't resolve
立即, 有錯誤說不能解破
this symbol for hint.
這符號暗示。
This references the album description text, but that was for the cheat sheet.
這關係於冊子形容文字, 但這是給暗示片。
Let's delete this and replace it with our own hint, which is Name.
讓我們刪去這個換作我們的暗示, 即是名字。
Since we want the name field at the top of our order form,
由於我們想要名字空位於訂購表的最上方，
above the toppings header, let's paste it right here.
於題目上方, 讓我們於這貼上。
It'll be the first child in this vertical linear layout.
這會是垂直線表上的第一個小童。
Now let's make sure that all the attributes are set the way that we want.
現在讓我們確認所有標誌都是我們想要的。
First, we have the view ID.
首先, 我們有顯示認證。
And it's called album_description_view.
而這叫做冊子形容顯示。
This is referring to the cheat sheet example, so
這是有關於暗示紙例子, 所以
let's change this to a more appropriate name.
讓我們改另一個較適合的名字。
Let's call it the name field.
讓我們叫做名字地方。
Next we have width and height which are familiar attributes.
之後我們有闊及高, 即是很相熟的標記。
Currently, the width of the edit text field is set to match parent.
現時, 更改文字地方的闊度與父母相乎。
That means the field will be as wide as the parent linear layout.
這意思是這空格的闊度會跟父母的線面一樣。
Next, we have height.
之後, 我們有高度。
Height is set to be wrap content, so
高度被設為包裝內容, 所以
it will be as tall as the content inside of it.
它會跟內容的高度一樣。
These two values seem reasonable, so let's leave them as is.
這2個值似乎很合理, 就他們這樣。
Next we have hint.
然後我們有暗示。
We haven't worked with this attribute before and
我們未似過用這標記及
there's an error saying that it can't resolve this string.
有錯誤說不能破解這串。
Let's look up the documentation for
讓我們找出文件去
EditText android to figure out what this attribute means.
改文字機械去破解這標記的意思。
By searching for edittext android we can find the documentation page for it.
於搜尋文字機械我們可以找到文件頁。
There's a quick class overview here and then a list of the XML attributes.
這裡有一個快速級別之有有XML標記清單。
It turns out that the edit text class inherits from text view and view.
這改文字級別繼承文字顯示及顯示。
So, that's why we have these inherited XML attributes.
所以我們有這些繼承的XML標記。
Once they're expanded we can search for android hint.
當他們被擴展我們可以搜尋到機械暗示。
All right this was the attribute we were looking for.
好了這是我們要找的標記。
If we scroll over to the right it says that
若我們滑到右手邊
this is the hint text to display when the text is empty.
這會在暗示空格內顯示文字是空白的。
This helps the user know what they show type in to that field.
這會幫用者知道這空格的類型。
In that app that I demonstrated to you, the hint text said name.
在我示範給你的程式, 暗示文字說是名字。
So in our code, we show erase this string and type in name.
在我們的編碼, 我們要擦掉串而打入名字。
Next we have the inputType.
Next we have the inputType. 之後我們有輸入類別。
This is also a new attribute, so let's look at the documentation.
這亦是一個新的標記, 就讓我們看看文件。
Now I'm going to search for Android input type.
現在我們搜尋機械輸入種類。
It's listed here and
在這有例明及
the description says, this is the type of data being placed in the text field.
形容說明, 這類數據是被放在文字空格。
It's used to help an input method decide how to let the user enter the text.
這是用來幫助輸入方法決定如何讓用者輸入文字。
This is a bit of a vague description, so let's click on this attribute for
這個形容有點不清晰, 所以讓我們按下標記
more information.
拿取更多資料。
Here’s the full description of InputType.
這裡是輸入類別的完全形容。
These are the possible values that we can set.
這些是可以設用的值。
In the example from the cheat sheet, the XML said textMultiLine.
在暗示紙內的例子, XML記多行文字。
Apparently this means that the edit text field can allow multiple lines of text.
這意思是更改文字空格可以容許多行文字。
We don’t expect someone’s name to be really long,
我們不預計有人的名字會很長,
so one line of text should be good enough.
所以一行的文字已足夠。
Let’s just use text as the input type.
讓我們用文字為輸入類別。
If I erase textMultiline and start typing text,
若我刪除多行文字而開始輸入文字,
I'll just select text and hit enter.
我會選取文字之後按進入。
Now I'm going to run the app on the device to check if the EditText
現在我們會在裝置執行程式去查看改文字會否
field shows up.
出現。
When the app launches, I see the name field.
當程式在執行, 我看到名字空格。
Awesome.
很好。
And I can type in to it as well.
而我可以在內打字。
But actually, it starts with a lowercase letter.
但其實,開始是用小草。
When I type, I want it to start as a capital letter.
當我打, 我想用大草開始。
To fix this, I can modify the input type here.
要解決這, 我可以更改輸入類別。
Let's look at the other options here.
讓我們看看其他選擇。
There's textCapcharacters, textCapwords, textCapsentences and
這有大草, 文字大草, 大草句字及
The ones about capitalization look promising.
有關大草的看來很好。
After reading through these descriptions,
看過這些形容後，
I think textCapwords could be a good option to try.
我想文字大草應該是一個很好的選擇。
So, let's copy this and use it.
所以讓我們複製這個來用。
And so, instead of text I'm going to use textCapwords.
所以我們用大草文字來取代文子。
Let's run the app again.
讓我們再執行程式。
Okay, now the keyboard starts with the letters capitalized, so
好了, 現在健盤由大草開始而
then I can just start typing the name, and if I add a space,
我可以開始打入名字, 若我加一個空格
then the next word is capitalized.
那下一個字便會是大草。
Awesome.
很好。
The last thing I notice is that we need a little bit of space
最後一樣東西是我們需要一些空格
in between this name field and the toppings header.
在名字空格及題目之間。
We've been adding 16 dp of vertical spacing, so let's do the same here.
我們已加了16DP的垂直空格, 所以讓我們在此做同樣的。
I could add it as bottom margin on the EditText field, but
我可以在底方加上改文字位置, 但
I'm just going to choose to add it as top margin on the toppings header.
我會選擇於題目行那方加上。
Okay, now the spacing looks and the name field is correct already.
好了, 現在有空格及名字地方又對了。
That took care of all the XML changes for step one.
這用一步處理了所以XML的改變。
Now we need to modify the java code.
現在我需要更改JAVA編碼。
For step two, when the order button is clicked,
第二步, 當命令按鈕被按,
we want to get the name from the text field and store it in a variable.
我們想於文字地方取得名字再儲成可變項。
It's easy for our human eyes to see the name in this field, but the Android
我們人類的眼很容易看到地方上的名字, 但機械
app doesn't know that we want to put this name in to the order summary here.
程式知道我們想把名字放於命令總結內。
It's still using Lyla's hard coded name.
它仍然在用Lyla的硬編碼名字。
This is just like how we had to figure out if the check box is checked or
這就好像我們查看複選框是否被選
not in order to update the order summary.
用來更新命令總結。
We haven't learned how to read text from EditText field, so
我們未學如何從改文字位置讀取文字, 所以
I'm going to search for how do I get text from the EditText field Android.
我會搜尋如何取得機械改文字位內的文字。
The first result looks good.
第一個結果看來很好。
It's a stack overflow question.
這是大量湧出的問題。
I can read the question but I'm mostly looking for the answer.
我可以讀到問題但我主要是在找答案。
I can scan through quickly to see if this page is helpful or not.
我可以快速看看這頁去看是否有用。
This answer has a green check mark by it and has a lot of upvotes, so
答案有綠色標記在旁, 所以
I start with the code snippet.
I start with the code snippet. 我用編碼片斷開始。
It looks like this code would go inside an activity class because we're calling
看來這編碼會在活動級別因為我們執行
We're trying to search the view hierarchy for a view with this ID.
我會嘗試用認證打顯示。
Once we find this view, we're casting it to an EditText view and
當我們找到顯示, 我們會設為改文字顯示之後
then storing that in a variable called text.
儲存為一個叫文字的可變項。
On the second line we're trying to declare a string variable called value.
在第二行, 我但試試宣告一串可變項叫值。
And store this inside of it.
之後儲在內。
Now this has a lot of parenthesis, and dots, and words, but you might be able
這個有很多括號, 點及字, 但你或許可以
to guess that we're trying to get the text out of this EditText field.
估計我們在試著在改文子空格內取得文字。
And we're trying to store it inside a string variable called value.
而我們會儲在串多變項內叫值。
Let's copy and paste this code in to our app to see if it works.
讓我們複製及貼上這編碼看看這程式是否可行。
In the MainActivity class I'm going to add the code in the submitOrder method.
在主活動級別內我會加一個輸出命令法方。
I chose this method because this is where the order button is getting
我選這個方法因為這是命令按鈕的地方
clicked and this is where we want to read from the name field.
按下而這是我們想看到的名字地方。
I'm going to paste the code from the stack overflow post into the top of
我會從擠滿的信上把編碼貼上
the method.
這方法。
Immediately there's an error that says it can't resolve this symbol.
立即有錯誤出現說不能解決這符號。
We need to replace this with the ViewId for the name field.
我們要用認證顯示取代名字位置。
Switching back to our layout.xml,
換回我的的layout.xml,
we gave the EditText field a view id of name_field,
我們給改文字位置顯示認證name_field,
so in the Java file, I'm going to change this to be R.id.name_field.
所以在JAVA檔案, 我會改為R.id.name_field.
There's no more errors, so I can try to run the app, but
再沒有錯誤, 我可以試試執行程式, 但
how will I know if this code is actually working or not?
我怎樣知道編碼是否可行?
I could add a log message here to verify
我可以加一個記錄信息去列明
that value actually holds the name in this field.
這位置的名字。
And here's the code for the log message.
而這是記錄信息的編碼。
I'm printing out name colon and then the value string.
我在印名字符號及串的價值。
Value is a vague name for this variable so
價值是一個多變項不清晰的名所以
I'm going to switch it to be called name.
我會改為叫名字。
That would be a little bit more of a descriptive name for it.
這會成為一多多一點描繪的名字。
Speaking of which, I'm going to change the variable name for
說開再說, 我會改多變名
EditText to also be name field.
改文字也成為名字位置。
Text could be confused with other things within our code.
這可能會跟其他編碼混亂。
Now let's run the app and check for this log message.
現在讓我們執行程式及找記錄信息。
Okay.
好了。
If I fill out the order form and
若我填上訂單及
then hit the order button, then I can check the logs here.
按下命令按鈕, 我便可以在這查看記錄。
I see a new message for MainActivity that says Name: Antigravity Anthony.
我看到新信息於主活動說:Antigravity Anthony.
So, it worked.
所以, 它可行。
This code actually did pull out the name from this field.
這編碼的確可以從位置中拿取名字。
Cool. Now that we have the user's name in
有型。現在我們有用者名字在
a variable, and we verified that with logging, that it's the correct name,
可變項內, 而我會用記錄澄清了這是正確的名,
then we can update the order summary to show this name.
然後我們可以更新命令總姞去表現這名。
In order for the order summary to show the correct name,
為了要讓命令總結顯示正確的名字,
we need to pass it as an input parameter to this method.
我們需要用輸入參數來通過這方法。
That means when we call the create order summary method,
這意思是我們命令制造命令總結方法,
we have to pass this name variable in as an input argument.
我會要用名字多變項來通過這輸入。
Let's make that change first.
Let's make that change first. 讓我但先改這個。
If I add name as an input argument,
若我加名字為輸入,
I get an error because the method call doesn't match the method signature.
我得到錯誤因為方法並不乎合方法簽證。
Scrolling down to the method definition,
滑下到方法釋義,
I can add String name as an input parameter.
我可以加串名為輸入參數。
I'll also update the Java doc as well.
我亦會同時更新JAVA文件。
Now, inside the createOrderSummary method, I can use this variable.
現在, 內部的制造命令總結方法內我可以用這可變項。
I'm going to erase the hard coded name and then concatenate this name variable.
我會刪除硬編碼及專主在這名字變項。
So, to recap, we're getting the name from the name_field and
所以, 重提, 我們在名字項內得到名字
then passing it as an input to the createOrderSummary method.
之後通過制造命令總結方法的輸入。
Inside this method, we can append the name to the order summary.
於這方法內, 我們可以附加命令總結名字。
Let's run the app to check our code.
讓我們執行程式去試試編碼。
then change the quantity.
改數量。
Then I can hit the order button.
之後我可以按命令按鈕。
Now I see that the order summary contains the name that I typed
現在我看到命令總結內有我早前
in earlier.
打的名字。
Woohoo!
嘩吓!
If I change the name and then hit order, then it updates again.
若我改名字之後按下命令, 那會再次更新。
That's exciting.
很興奮。
Now that everything in the app is working, I can remove this log message.
現時程式都可行, 我可以拿走這記錄信息。
I can run the app again one more time to make sure that things work.
我可以再次執行程式去確定所有事都可行。
Now let's go back and answer these quiz questions.
現在讓我們回去答測驗內的問題。
The view that we added to our app is called EditText.
我們加上程式上的顯示叫改文字。
The second question asks what Java method we called
第二個問題問JAVA方法叫什麼
to get the text from this view.
才可得到文字顯示。
We can answer this by going back to our code.
我們可以回到編碼回答這問題。
We search the view hierarchy for
我們在顯示等級體系
theEditText java object that represented the name field.
找改文字JAVA物件去代表名字。
We store that in a variable called nameField.
我們儲於叫名字空位的可變項。
And on that object we called the method.
而在物件我們叫作方法。
We called the getText method, which takes no input arguments and
我們叫取文字方法, 它不收輸入的
it has a return value of another object.
它的回值為另個物件。
That leads us to our third question.
這牽領我們到第三個問題。
What's the return data type of the getText method?
這回取文字方法的回值數據是什麼?
The answer is editable and
這答案是可改變的及
I figured this out by looking at the Android documentation.
我是從機械文件中找到的。
For the Edit Text Class, if you scroll down you can see all the public methods.
於改文字級別, 若你滑下你可以看到公共方法。
GetText is listed as a method as returning the text that the text view is
取文字是列於方法作為回值文字
displaying.
所顯示。
The return data type is editable.
回值數據類是可改變的。
This returns an editable object, and we can call another method on this object
這回了一個可改變物件, 而我們叫這為另一個物件方法
by adding the dot notation and then the method name.
加上點號之後名字方法。
So in this case we're calling the toString method on the editable object,
所以在這情況我會執行串方法於可改物件,
and the toString method returns a string, so
而串方法回一個串值, 所以
that can be stored in the name variable.
這可以於名字變項內儲存。
This is a more advanced concept, and it's called chaining method calls.
這是一個比較深的概念, 而這叫串方法命令。
Because we're calling one method, getting the return value and
因為我們在執行一個方法, 得到回值之後
then calling another method and if this returns an object,
執行另一方法而若回了一個物件
you can call another method on it.
你可以執行另一個方法。
And you can keep calling methods one after the other.
而你不停執行命令。
The reason we chain method calls is because getText method returns
我會串方法的原因是得到文字方法回值
an editable object.
一個可變物件。
An editable object cannot be stored inside a string variable,
一個可變物件不可以作儲存為可變的串
as seen by this Android Studio error saying incompatible types.
機械板會顯示不相乎類別。
So, if we add the toString method, then the return value of this whole thing is
所以若我們加串方法, 之後回值會
a string, and that can be stored in the name variable.
是串值, 而可以儲為可變名字。
We can verify this by checking the documentation.
我會可以查看文件來驗證。
The getText method returns an editable object.
取文字方法回了可變物件。
If I click on this, in the editable class,
若我按下, 於可變級別
we should find a method called toString.
我們可找到叫串的方法。
Scrolling down,
向下滑,
in the public method section, I don't see toString listed here.
於公共方法, 我們看不到清單例了串。
But there are inherited methods.
但這有繼承方法。
So, if I open this drop down, then I see that toString is a method.
所以, 若我打開向下, 我可看到串方法。
And the return value is string.
而回值是串。
So, to hammer it home one more time, this method call returns an editable
所以若我再按一次, 這方法回一個可變
object, and then we can call the toString method on it.
項, 之後可以執行串方法。
The toString method returns a string and so
串方法回一個串值之後
this whole thing on the right hand side here, returns a string.
右手邊的全部, 會回一個串。
And that can be stored in the string variable called name.
而我們可以儲可變串叫名字。
Wow, that was a really long coding task.
嘩, 這編碼任務真長。
You can take a quick break now and then come back because we need to
你現在可以休息一下再回來因為我們需要
figure out how to change the price based on what the user ordered.
找到如何改用者命令的價錢。
We're going to do this by learning about control flow.
我們會用控制流程去學習。